We all make a little extra effort to look nice for special occasions.
我们都会为特殊场合多下一点功夫，让自己看起来体面一些。
But most of us have conflicting feelings about dressing up and feel guilty about taking the time to focus on clothes.
但我们大多数人对精心打扮怀有矛盾的心理，也会因为花时间关注衣着而感到内疚。
Science now suggests the right dress may give us the extra edge in our professional and personal lives.
如今科学表明，合适的着装或许能让我们在职业和个人生活中多一分优势。
We hear sayings like “dress for the job you want, not the job you have”.
我们会听到“为你想要的工作着装，而不是为你现有的工作着装”之类的说法。
Most people don’t really believe in them, but research into the impact of clothes on behavior now suggests that there may actually be a grain of truth in these sayings.
大多数人并不真的相信这些说法，但如今对衣着如何影响行为的研究表明，这些说法或许确实有一点道理。
Science says that the clothes we wear affect our behavior, our mood and even the way we interact with others because of the symbolic meaning that we assign to different types of clothing.
科学告诉我们，由于我们给不同类型的服装赋予了象征意义，所穿的衣服会影响我们的行为和情绪，甚至影响我们与他人互动的方式。
We consider some clothes to be powerful, some to be fun, and so on.
我们认为有些衣服很有气势，有些衣服很有趣，诸如此类。
We even evaluate people whom we have just met based on their clothes.
我们甚至会根据衣着来评价刚认识的人。
We also evaluate ourselves based on what we are wearing because of the way it makes us feel.
我们也会根据自己身上穿的衣服来评价自己，原因就在于这身衣服带给我们的感觉。
This means that the experience of wearing something affects our attitudes and our choice of behavior.
这意味着，穿某件衣服的体验会影响我们的态度和行为选择。
There’s a reason tailored jackets are associated with being “dressed for success”.
人们把剪裁合身的西装外套和“为成功而着装”联系在一起，是有原因的。
It seems that wearing formal office wear puts us in the right frame of mind to conduct business.
看来，穿上正式的职业装能让我们进入适合处理业务的心态。
Wearing power clothing makes us feel more confident and even increases hormones needed for displaying dominance.
穿上彰显权势的服装会让我们感觉更自信，甚至会提高展现支配地位所需的激素水平。
This in turn helps us become better negotiators and abstract thinkers.
这进而帮助我们成为更出色的谈判者和抽象思考者。
While a good suit works wonders for our performance in the boardroom, wearing formal wear isn’t a great idea when we want to socialize.
虽然在董事会会议室里，一套好西装对我们的表现有奇效，但想要社交时，穿正装就不是什么好主意了。
Studies have found that people tend to be less open and less able to relax when they wear formal clothes.
研究发现，人们穿正装时往往不那么放得开，也不那么容易放松。
On the other hand, casual dress helps us become more friendly and creative.
另一方面，便装有助于我们变得更友善、更有创造力。
These findings support the idea of wearing business casuals on a Friday, since colleagues are most likely to take time out to socialize on the last work day of the week.
这些发现支持了周五穿商务休闲装这一想法，因为在一周的最后一个工作日，同事们最有可能抽出时间来社交。
I mean, who wants to hang out with people in their suits?
我的意思是，谁会想和穿着西装的人一起消磨时光呢？